(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
回れ回れ回れ回れ
Spin, spin, spin, spin
回れ！
Spin!
気が付けば　いつしか
Before I knew it, at some point...
五感は　塞げ塞げ
My five senses were shut out, shut out
未だ見ぬ　誰そ彼
To the someone I've yet to see
行方　知らず知らず
I'm unaware of their whereabouts
真白に　降り積もる
Piling up in pure white
心の　氷柱氷柱
The icicles of my heart, icicles
想いは　淡雪か
Are my feelings light snow?
溶けては　消えて消えて
Melting and disappearing, disappearing
遠き日の　約束は
The promise from a distant day
霞む　幻
Is a hazy phantom
浮世の　定めなら
If it's the fate of this fleeting world
運命　抗え抗え
Then resist destiny, resist it
宵闇を　照らせ照らせ
Light up the twilight, light it up
紅蓮に　燃やせ燃やせ
Burn it in crimson, burn it
巡り巡る　季節の中
In the cycle of seasons
夢の終わりを　追いかけて
Chasing the end of a dream
咲き誇れよ　花のように
Bloom proudly like a flower
凛と美しく　在るために
To remain dignified and beautiful
強く　強く
Strongly, strongly
生き抜いて　生き抜いて
Survive, survive
一雫　こぼれた
A single drop fell
涙は　焦げ焦げ
My tears are scorched, scorched
時の　狭間に
In the gap of time
一人　独り独り
Alone, all alone
宵顔で　差し出す
Offering with a twilight face
蜜は　どけどけ
The nectar is pushed away, pushed away
古の　傷跡
Ancient scars
撫でては　濡れて濡れて
Caressed and becoming wet, wet
篝火に　照らされて
Illuminated by the bonfire
揺れる　面影
The swaying visage
祈りの　鐘響け
Sound the bell of prayer
命　尽くせ尽くせ
Give your life, give it all
空の果てへ　飛ばせ飛ばせ
Fly to the edge of the sky, fly there
十六夜の月を　捕らえ捕らえ
Capture the sixteenth-night moon, capture it
巡り巡る　宿命の中
In the cycle of destiny
花の宴を　楽しんで
Enjoying the feast of flowers
舞い踊れよ　姫のように
Dance like a princess
飽きもせずに　歌うために
To sing without getting tired
遠く　遠く
Far, far away
響かせて　響かせて
Let it echo, let it echo
回れ回れ回れ回れ
Spin, spin, spin, spin
回れ！
Spin!
雪月花に　回れ回れ
Spin for the snow, moon, and flowers
ありがとうございますー！
Thank you very much!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
はぁ……はぁ……みんな、ありがとう！
Phew... Thank you, everyone!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
えーと、今日は私の誕生日3Dライブに来てくれて本当にありがとう！
Um, thank you so much for coming to my birthday 3D live today!
そして3期生のみんなも、一緒に歌ってくれてありがとう！
And thank you to all the 3rd gen members for singing with me!
おめでとー！
Happy birthday!
嬉しい～！最初は「回れ！雪月花」でした～！
I'm so happy! The first song was "Maware! Setsugetsuka"!
回れ回れしたね～
We really turned and turned, didn't we?
目が回るぺこ～
I'm dizzy-peko~
るしちゃん、おめでとう！
Rushi-chan, congratulations!
ありがとうマリン……あ、マリンちゃん！
Thank you, Marine... I mean, Marine-chan!
先輩でいいよ！
Senpai is fine!
今日はめでたい日なので、どんどん盛り上がっていきたいと思います！
Today is a special day, so I want to keep the excitement building!
次の曲は何かな？
I wonder what the next song is?
次は……これです！
Next is... this!
ないない
Nai Nai
Lyric: ハヤシケイ / Music: 毛蟹
Lyrics: Kei Hayashi / Music: Kegani
ない　じゃない
No, it's not
曖昧な愛
An ambiguous love
色の無いアイ
A colorless eye
期待　意外
Expectations, unexpected
他人事みたい
Like it's someone else's problem
おかげ様　どちら様
Thanks to you, but who are you?
答え様々
Answers are various
何者でもないまま
While remaining as a nobody
何も出来ないまま
While remaining unable to do anything
生きるのは無駄ですか？
Is it pointless to live?
悪い事ですか？
Is it a bad thing?
ここに居ない居ない居ないのは
The one who isn't here, here, here...
自分　自分
...is me, myself
誰も居ない居ない居ないまま
With no one else around, around, around...
明け捨ててさよなら
Empty it out and say goodbye
嬉しくない　哀しくももうない
I'm not happy, and I'm not even sad anymore
透明な気分
A transparent feeling
足りない自分　合わす顔もない
My lacking self has no face to show
ない
No
笑えないじゃない
I can't even laugh, can I?
這いつくばい　閉じたままかい
Crawling on the ground, are you still closed off?
返事はい
The answer is "yes"
期待だけ抱き
Holding on only to expectations
いやいや投げられた賽
Reluctantly, the die was cast
てめえは知らない
You don't know a thing
ここに居たい居たい居たいのも
The one who wants to stay, stay, stay here...
自分　自分
...is me, myself
味わう苦い苦い苦いまま
While tasting the bitterness, bitterness, bitterness...
当てどなくさよなら
Saying goodbye aimlessly
堪えられない　行く先ももうない
Unbearable, there's nowhere left to go
迷子の気分
The feeling of a lost child
間違えてない　また分からない
I haven't made a mistake, but I still don't know
ない
No
どうだっていいじゃない
It doesn't matter anyway, does it?
影も形も いっそ失くしてしまえばいい
I might as well just lose shadow and form altogether.
またハイ ひとつひとつから始めればいい
Again, yes, I should just start over one by one.
ここにいない いない いないのは自分 自分
The one who is not here, not here, not here is myself, myself.
誰も見ない 見ない 見ないまま 空きステでさよなら
Without anyone seeing, seeing, seeing, goodbye at the empty stage.
嬉しくない 悲しくもない 透明な気分
Not happy, not sad, a transparent feeling.
足りない自分 合わせる顔もない
My insufficient self has no face to show.
ない ない ないままで ここにいたい いたい
Just as I am, with nothing, nothing, nothing, I want to be here, be here.
笑いたいじゃない
I want to laugh, don't I?
せーの！
One, two!
でも そんなんじゃだめ
But that's not good.
もう そんなんじゃほら
Look, that's already no good.
心は進化するよ もっともっと
My heart will evolve, more and more.
言葉にすれば消えちゃう関係なら 言葉を消せばいいやって思ってた
I thought if it was a relationship that would disappear if put into words, then I should just erase the words.
恐れてた だけどあれ？ なんか違うかも
I was afraid, but wait? Something might be different.
千里の道も一歩から 石のように固い そんな意志で
A journey of a thousand miles begins with a single step, with a will as hard as a stone.
塵も積もればやまとなでしこ？ 死ぬ気で いや死ぬ気で！
If dust piles up, will it become a Yamato Nadeshiko? With all my might, no, with my life on the line!
ふわふわり ふわふわる あなたが名前を呼ぶ それだけで宙へ浮かぶ
Fluffy and soft, when you call my name, just that makes me float into the air.
ふわふわる ふわふわり あなたが笑っている それだけで笑顔になる
Soft and fluffy, when you are smiling, just that makes me smile.
神様ありがとう 運命のいたずらでも
Thank you, God, even if it's a prank of fate.
めぐり逢えたことが 幸せなの
I'm happy just for the fact that we were able to meet.
でも そんなんじゃだめ
But that's not good.
もう そんなんじゃほら
Look, that's already no good.
心は進化するよ もっともっと
My heart will evolve, more and more.
そう そんなんじゃやだ
Yes, I don't want it to be like that.
ねぇ そんなんじゃまだ
Hey, it's not enough like that.
私のこと見ててね ずっとずっと
Please keep looking at me, forever and ever.
私の中のあなたほど あなたの中の私の存在は まだまだ大きくないこともわかってるけれど
I know that my existence in you is not yet as large as yours in me, but...
今この同じ瞬間 共有してる実感
The feeling of sharing this same moment right now.
塵も積もればやまとなでしこ？ 略してちりつもやまとなでこ！
If dust piles up, will it become a Yamato Nadeshiko? Abbreviated as Chiritsumo Yamato Nadeko!
くらくらり くらくらる あなたを見上げたら それだけで眩しすぎて
Dizzy and spinning, when I look up at you, just that is too dazzling.
くらくらる くらくらり あなたを想っている それだけで溶けてしまう
Spinning and dizzy, when I think of you, just that makes me melt away.
神様ありがとう 運命のいたずらでも
Thank you, God, even if it's a prank of fate.
めぐり逢えたことが 幸せなの
I'm happy just for the fact that we were able to meet.
恋する季節は 欲張りサーキュレーション
The season of love is a greedy circulation.
恋する気持ちは 欲張りサーキュレーション
The feeling of love is a greedy circulation.
恋する瞳は 欲張りサーキュレーション
The eyes in love are a greedy circulation.
恋する乙女は 欲張りサーキュレーション
A maiden in love is a greedy circulation.
ふわふわり ふわふわる あなたが名前を呼ぶ それだけで宙へ浮かぶ
Fluffy and soft, when you call my name, just that makes me float into the air.
ふわふわる ふわふわり あなたが笑っている それだけで笑顔になる
Soft and fluffy, when you are smiling, just that makes me smile.
神様ありがとう 運命のいたずらでも
Thank you, God, even if it's a prank of fate.
めぐり逢えたことが 幸せなの
I'm happy just for the fact that we were able to meet.
巡り合えたことが幸せなの
It's happiness that we were able to meet
でもそんなんじゃだめ もうそんなんじゃほら 心は進化するよ もっともっと
But that's no good, look, my heart will evolve more and more
そうそんなんじゃやだ ねぇそんなんじゃまだ 私のこと見ててね ずっとずっと
Yeah, I don't like that, hey, not like that yet, keep looking at me forever and ever
はい！
Yes!
恋愛サーキュレーション、ノエルと恋愛サーキュレーションでした。ありがとうございました。
That was Renai Circulation, Renai Circulation with Noel. Thank you very much.
どうじても伝えたくて、るしあ... ありがとうありがとう。
I really wanted to tell you, Rushia... Thank you, thank you.
お誕生日おめでとう。
Happy birthday.
そうなんよ。１６００歳になっちまったよ。
That's right. I've turned 1600 years old.
あれ？でも１６００歳で... え？
Huh? But at 1600... eh?
永遠の１６００歳ってこと？
You mean an eternal 1600 years old?
いやもうそれ以上もそれ以下も年取らないから。
I won't get any older or younger than that.
なるほどな。
I see.
恒久的な存在。
A permanent existence.
ノエル、誕生日だからお願いがあるんだけど。
Noel, since it's my birthday, I have a favor to ask.
どうしたの？お願いって。
What is it? A favor?
え、聞いてくれる？
Will you listen to it?
何？
What?
あ、一言だけ言っとくけど、大胸筋はあげられないからね。
Um, I'll just say one thing, I can't give you my pectoral muscles.
うるさいよ！いらない！うるさいよ！もう！タップしてるんだから。魔法で。いいの！
Shut up! I don't want them! Shut up! Jeez! I'm 'tapping' them with magic. It's fine!
え、ちょっとさ、ちょっとさ、ちょっとさ、ちょっとさ...
Uh, hey, hey, hey, hey...
お願いごとなんだけどさ、ママになってほしいんだ。
My request is... I want you to become my mama.
ママ？
Mama?
あら、どうしたの？
Oh, what's wrong?
え、ちょっとあの、最近ほら、去年とかさ、ちょっとお仕事いっぱいあってさ、疲れちゃってさ。
Well, you know, lately, like last year, I've had a lot of work and I'm a bit tired.
るしあ頑張ってたもんね。
You've been working hard, Rushia.
ありがとう。ちょっとあの、膝枕とかしてほしい。
Thank you. Um, I'd like you to give me a lap pillow.
わかった。じゃあ団長の膝においで。
I understand. Then, come to the Knight-Captain's lap.
やった！やったやった！え、いいのいいの？本当にいいの？いいよ。
Yay! Yay, yay! Wait, is it okay, is it okay? Are you sure? It's okay.
お邪魔します。よいしょ。
Excuse me. Up we go.
よしよし、可愛いね。ノエルママ、よしよし。
There, there, you're cute. Noel mama, there, there.
いつも頑張って偉いね。
You're good for always working hard.
ありがとう。ああ癒される。本当になでなでして。
Thank you. Ah, this is healing. Really, stroke my head.
よしよし、生きてるだけで偉いよ。おねぇーちゃん...
There, there, you're great just for being alive. Big sister...
やべ、やべ、みんな見てた。
Oh no, oh no, everyone was watching.
あ、やば、ライブだったわこれ。
Ah, oh no, this was a live stream.
やばやば... ちょっと今日のことは忘れてください。すみません。
Oh no... Please forget about today's events. Sorry.
あのさ、せっかくだからさ、記念撮影しない？
Hey, since we're here, why don't we take a commemorative photo?
そうだね、みんな見てるしね。
That's right, since everyone is watching.
そうそうそう。え、ちょっと一緒にさ、お写真撮ろう。
Yeah, yeah. Let's take a picture together.
何を撮るんだい？
What should we take?
こうやってこう、近づいて、ぎゅー！
Like this, get close, and hug!
いいね、さっきの終わりのポーズ。そう。
Good idea, like the pose at the end earlier. Right.
ちょっと上からカメラさん撮れますか？
Mr. Camera, can you take a shot from above?
上から。ああ、ちっちゃくて可愛いよ。
From above. Ah, you're so small and cute.
ちょっと胸邪魔じゃね？邪魔じゃないよ、当たってないでしょ。
Isn't your chest in the way? It's not, it's not touching you.
セーフ。次、ちょっとさ、ぶりっ子しない？
Safe. Next, hey, shall we act cute?
ぶりっ子。ああいいね、可愛さアピールしてくか。
Act cute. Good idea, let's appeal with our cuteness.
ちょっとぶりっ子しよ、ぶりっ子。ぶりぶり。可愛い？
Let's act cute. So cute. Am I cute?
可愛くて、いっぱい撮って。いっぱい撮ってね。
You're cute, take lots of pictures. Take lots, okay?
ウインクとかしちゃおうかな。ウインク。ウインク。
Maybe I'll do a wink. Wink. Wink.
最後にさ、後ろに背景のイラスト流れたのわかる？あれでそのポーズしたいんだけど。
Finally, do you know the background illustration that played? I want to do that pose.
ああ、いいね、いいね。いい？
Ah, good idea. Is it okay?
出せるかな？スタジオの方。あ、出た！
Can you bring it up, Studio? Ah, it appeared!
これさ、のりおママがね、描いてくれてね、めっちゃ上手！めっちゃ上手！
This, Norio-mama drew it for me, and she's so good! So good!
そう、このポーズしよ。可愛いでしょ。フリー素材です。
Yeah, let's do this pose. It's cute, right? This is free material.
後でツイッターとかに載っけてあげてください。いっぱい撮ってね。
Please post it on Twitter later. Take lots of pictures.
もっとさ、ここ、アップとかできますか？カメラさん。
Can you zoom in more here? Mr. Camera.
ありがとうございます。うわ、可愛い！可愛い！
Thank you very much. Whoa, cute! Cute!
メイドるしあ、メイドさん。満足しちゃったから、もう...
Maid Rushia, a maid. I'm satisfied now, so...
このままノエルママの膝の上でお寝寝する。うん、そうだね。
I'll just sleep on Noel mama's lap like this. Yeah, that's right.
ちょっと休む。休憩します。いっぱい休んで。
I'll rest for a bit. Taking a break. Get plenty of rest.
よしよし、ノエルママ、よしよしして。えらいね。
There, there. Noel mama, there, there me. You're good.
おやすみだよ。よしよし。
It's time to sleep. There, there.
ちょっと寝るね。おやすみ。おやすみ。
I'm going to sleep for a bit. Good night. Good night.
雨とカプチーノ / Lyric / Music : n-buna
Rain and Cappuccino / Lyric / Music : n-buna
灰色のしらんだ　心はカプチーノ
The grey dawn, my heart is like a cappuccino
みたいな色してる
It's that kind of color
言い訳はいいよ　窓辺に置いてきて
It's okay to leave your excuses by the window
数え切れないよ
They're countless
灰色のしらんだ　心はカプチーノ
The grey dawn, my heart is like a cappuccino
みたいな色して
It's that kind of color
言い訳はいいよ　虚（うつ）ろカプチーノ
It's okay to leave your excuses, a hollow cappuccino
おどけたふりして
Pretending to be playful
さあ揺蕩（たゆた）うように雨流れ
Now, as if swaying, the rain flows
僕らに嵐、花に溺れ
A storm for us, drowning in flowers
君が褪（あ）せないような思い出をどうか
Please, let there be memories so you won't fade
どうか
Please...
どうか君が溢（あふ）れないように
Please, so that you don't overflow
波も使いがくれない　夕挿（ゆうさ）し
The waves are of no use, the evening light
窓に反射して
Reflecting in the window
八月の微睡（まどろ）み　潮騒、待ちぼうけ
August's slumber, the sound of the tide, waiting in vain
海風一つで
With a single sea breeze
夏を泳いだ花の白さよ
Oh, the whiteness of the flowers that swam through summer
否（いな）め、流れ夜に溺れ
Deny it, drown in the flowing night
誰も褪（あ）せないような花一つ　どうか
Just one flower that no one can fade, please...
どうか
Please...
どうか胸の内側に挿（さ）して
Please, insert it inside my chest
ずっとおかしな生き方一つを教えてほしいだけ
I just want you to tell me about a way of life that's been strange all along
払えるものなんて僕にはもうないけど
Though I have nothing left to pay with
何も答えられないなら　言葉一つでもいいよ
If you can't answer anything, even a single word is fine
分からないよ　本当に分かんないんだよ
I don't know, I really don't know
さあ揺蕩（たゆた）うように雨流れ
Now, as if swaying, the rain flows
僕らに嵐、花に溺れ
A storm for us, drowning in flowers
君が褪（あ）せないように書く詩（うた）を　どうか
The poem I write so you won't fade, please...
どうか
Please...
どうか今も忘れないように
Please, so that I won't forget even now
また一つ夏が渡って　花一つを胸に抱いて
Another summer passes, holding a single flower to my chest
流れは詩（うた）の裏で
The flow is behind the poem
君が褪（あ）せないようにこの詩（うた）を　どうか
This poem, so that you won't fade, please...
どうか
Please...
君が溢（あふ）れないように
So that you don't overflow
わー！
Waa!
おめでとう！
Happy Birthday!
ありがとう！嬉しいよー！
Thank you! I'm so happy!
雨とカプチーノでした！
That was "Rain and Cappuccino"!
うわー、めっちゃ難しかったー！
Whoa, that was really hard!
難しかったー！
It was hard!
ふーたんのヨルシカさんめちゃくちゃいいね！
Fu-tan singing Yorushika is amazing!
いや、ルシアのがさ、やっぱ合ってるなって思ったんだよね。
I really thought it suited Rushia, after all.
いやいやいや、提案してくれたのふーたんなんだよね。
No, no, no, it was Fuu-tan who suggested it.
最初はね、夜鹿さん絶対ルシアと一緒に歌いたいって思ってたから、歌えて良かった。
At first, I really wanted to sing Yorushika with Rushia, so I'm glad we could.
本当にありがとう。なんかね、ルシアが夜鹿さん好きなの分かっててくれて、うん。
Thank you so much. It's like, you knew I liked Yorushika, yeah.
ふーたんも好きなんだよね、確か。
And Fuu-tan likes them too, I believe.
そう。でもね、今回初めて歌ったんだよ、ルシアと。
Right. But this was the first time I sang it with Rushia.
結局選んでくれたじゃない。
But you ended up picking it in the end.
そうなの。私が夜鹿さん歌いたいと思ってて、いろいろね、なんか候補とかを出したし、ルシアからも出してくれてて。
That's right. I wanted to sing Yorushika, so I put out some candidates, and Rushia gave some too.
結局この選んだ、結果的に選んだこの『雨とカプチーノ』。
In the end, this 'Rain and Cappuccino' that we chose...
それをさ、ルシアが決めてくれたのって、結局何がきっかけだったの？
...what was the reason you decided on it, Rushia?
あのね、すっごく迷ったの。
Well, I was really torn.
うん。
Yeah.
迷ったんだけど、この『雨とカプチーノ』ってさ、すごくなんか切ないじゃん。
I was torn, but this 'Rain and Cappuccino' is really sad, right?
うん。
Yeah.
こう、なんていうのかな、心がしゅんってなるような、でも温かくなるような、なんていうのかな。
It's like, how should I say... it makes your heart feel tight, but also warm, you know?
うーん、難しいね。
Hmm, it's hard to describe.
すごく難しいんだけど、それをね、ふーたんと歌いたいなって、こうインスピレーションで思った。
It's very difficult, but I felt like I wanted to sing it with Fuu-tan, by inspiration.
絶対に合うなって思ったんだよね。
I thought it would definitely fit us.
えー、嬉しい！
Oh, I'm so happy!
そう、だから二人でやっぱさ、合うのがいいじゃん。
Right, so it's best if it fits both of us, you know.
どっちかだけじゃなくて。そうそうそう、なんかそのエモさみたいなのも入れたくてね。
Not just one of us. Yeah, I wanted to include that kind of emotional vibe too.
えへ、なんか真面目な話しちゃった。
Ehe, I ended up talking seriously.
いつもは「うわぁー！」って言ってるのに。
Even though you're usually like 'Waaaa!'
今日はしおらしくて可愛いんじゃない？
Don't I look demure and cute today?
ちょっとー、ちょっと照れちゃうじゃん、ふーたん。
Hey, that's embarrassing, Fuu-tan.
いいんだよ、「あー！」って言っても。
It's fine even if you go 'Ah!'
やだよ、今日はアイドルだからね。誕生日だし。
No way, I'm an idol today. It's my birthday after all.
あ、そっか。そうだよね。じゃあさ、なんかアイドルっぽいさ、撮影とか一緒にする？
Ah, right. That's true. Then, shall we take some idol-like photos together?
え、しよしよしよ！せっかくだからしよう！
Oh, let's do it, let's do it! Since we're here, let's do it!
え、じゃあちょっとポーズしようポーズ。
Okay, let's strike a pose, a pose.
いいよ。え、どうする？どうしようかな？
Sure. Okay, what should we do? Let's see...
あ、いいいね、これにしよ。あ、これにしよ！
Oh, this is good, let's do this. Let's do this!
これして、アイドルね。
Do this, like an idol.
あ、撮って、みんな撮って撮って。
Ah, take pictures, everyone take pictures, take pictures.
撮ってください。上からとか、横からとか。
Please take pictures. From above, or from the side.
うーん、いいねいいねいいね。
Hmm, nice, nice, nice.
あ、可愛いね。
Ah, it's cute.
自分で言うのもなんだけど、可愛いね。
It's weird to say it myself, but it's cute.
あとハート作ろ、こうやってさ。
Also, let's make a heart, like this.
あ、いいね。難しいよ、ハート。いけるかな？
Ah, nice. It's hard, a heart. Can we do it?
腰に、腰に、腰に...
On the waist, the waist, the waist...
あ、あ、すごいすごい、できてる、できてる。
Oh, oh, amazing, we're doing it, we're doing it.
できたできた。やったー、可愛い可愛い。
We did it, we did it. Yay, so cute, so cute.
可愛い、できてる。
Cute, we're doing it.
やったー、めっちゃ上手く歌えた、ふーたんと。やったねー。
Yay, I could sing so well with Fuu-tan. We did it!
やったねー。
We did it!
ふー、ちょっと休んじゃお。
Whew, let me rest a bit.
休むな休むな。
Don't rest, don't rest.
うわー。
Uwaa.
おいおいおい、まだまだ終わらないでしょ。ほら、立ちな。
Hey, hey, it's not over yet. Come on, stand up.
立ちな、ふーたん。
Stand up, Fuu-tan.
連れてってくれるの？
Are you going to take me with you?
そうだよ。次の、次のステージに行ってもらうから。行こう。
That's right. I'm going to have you go to the next stage. Let's go.
頑張るねー。
I'll do my best.
チューリングラブ
Lyric : ナユタ セイジ/ナナヲアカリ / Music : ナユタ セイジ
Turing Love
Lyrics: Nayuta Seiji/Nanawo Akari / Music: Nayuta Seiji
言葉で表せない感情 3 2 1
Emotions that can't be expressed in words 3 2 1
解析不能なこの感情 3 2 1
These unanalyzable emotions 3 2 1
あー 証を 証明を
Ah, the proof, the demonstration
Q.E.D.
もっともっと 恋の定義
More and more, the definition of love
もっともっと 愛の定理
More and more, the theorem of love
教えてよ もっともっともっと
Tell me more, more, more
ABC? or Q.E.D.?
解析は終わらない
The analysis never ends
ふー！あー！
Phew! Ahh!
るしあちゃんおめでとう！
Rushia-chan, happy birthday!
ありがとー！チューリングラブどうだったー？
Thank you! How was "Tuning Love"?
うん！どうだった？
Yeah! How was it?
いやー幸せでしたね。なんか二人でこんなイチャイチャと踊っちゃったりなんかして。
I was so happy. We were flirting and dancing together like that.
嬉しかったねー、イチャイチャしちゃったね。
I was happy too. We really flirted, didn't we?
しちゃったねー、ねー。
We did, didn't we?
楽しかったわー。いつもね、別の曲だったけど、初めて歌ったからね。
It was fun. We usually sing different songs, but this was our first time with this one.
ねー。新鮮だった。
Yeah. It felt fresh.
ねー。踊りもね、めちゃめちゃ可愛くて、大変で。でも楽しかったー。思い出になった、思い出に。
Right. The dance was super cute, though it was hard. But it was fun! A great memory.
思い出になった。ダンス頑張ったね。
A great memory. You worked hard on the dance.
ねー。頑張った頑張ったー。
Yeah. I really did.
ねー。キレキレ。
Yeah. You were sharp.
ねー。ねー、ねー、ねー。
Yeah. Hey, hey, hey...
なんですか？
What is it?
なんかちょっと冷たくない？
Aren't you being a bit cold?
え？
Eh?
なに急に...
What's this all of a sudden...
なんかさ、もっとあったかくしてよー。
Like, be warmer to me.
えー？あったかく？じゃあちょっと抱きしめちゃうかな。ちょっと、はい、おいで、はい。
Eh? Warmer? Then maybe I should give you a hug. Come here.
ちょっ、ちょっ、近い、近い。さっき...もう、近いよ！
Wait, wait, too close, too close. Just now... Jeez, you're too close!
あれ？さっき、あれ？
Huh? Just now... what?
さっきはこれ近づいてばっかじゃん。
You were the one getting close just now.
えー？何回近づいたっていいでしょ。
Eh? What's wrong with getting close a few times?
あったかいでしょ。何が嫌なんだよ、言ってみろ。
It's warm, right? Tell me what you don't like about it.
離れて、ちょっと、離れて。あ、でもマリンマリン、でもさ、今のいい。今のちょっとみんなに写真撮ってもらおう。
Get away, a bit, get away. Ah, but Marine, Marine, that was good. Let's have everyone take a photo of that.
あ、確かに。ちょっと撮ってもらいましょうか。
Ah, true. Let's have them take some.
え、じゃあ今ので、撮ってね。
Okay, take a photo like that.
はい、今撮って、撮ってね。
Yes, take a photo now.
はい、みなさーん。はい、どうぞどうぞー。
Yes, everyone. Here you go.
撮ってください。どうですか？
Please take photos. How is it?
どうですか？
How is it?
クンカクンカ。
*Sniff sniff*
るし...離れて、ちょっと。もう、マリンおしまい！はいおしまい！
Rushi... Get away, a bit. Okay, Marine, that's enough! Enough!
もう、なんか釣れないなー。
Jeez, you're so cold.
おしまい。まだもう一ポーズくらい撮ってもらえますか？
Enough. Can we have one more pose?
え、なんか撮る撮る。
Eh, sure, let's take one.
やっぱちょっとチューリングラブさ、ほら踊ったからさ。
Since we danced "Tuning Love"...
チューリングラブのポーズしますか？
...should we do a "Tuning Love" pose?
いいですね。やりましょうやりましょう。
Good idea. Let's do it.
チュー...どうですか？
Tuning... how is it?
はい。可愛いでしょー。写真撮ってね。
Here. It's cute, right? Take photos.
いい。良くない？
Good. Isn't it good?
可愛いね。胸のサイズの差が際立っている。
Cute. The difference in chest size is really standing out.
うるさいよ！本当にさ、そういうの脂肪じゃん。
Shut up! Seriously, that's just fat!
あー、いつものが始まりましたね。
Ah, here we go again.
あー、そのいつもの話はね、いいとして。
Ah, let's put that usual talk aside.
いやでも、るしあさ、うん。
But anyway, Rushia...
なんか、あのさ、今嫌なこと思い出いだしちゃったな。
I just remembered something unpleasant.
え、何何？
Eh? What is it?
船長の、100万人記念の時に、一緒に、にゃんせー歌ったじゃん。
Back during my 1 million milestone, we sang "Nyanse" together, right?
あれさ、なんか、おかゆ先輩と歌ってたよね？
In that video, you were singing it with Okayu-senpai, weren't you?
いや、おかゆ先輩マジかっこよかったなー。
Man, Okayu-senpai was seriously cool.
あ、あ、もしかして、チューリングラブも。
Ah, ah... wait, maybe "Tuning Love" too...
まさかチューリングラブもおかゆ先輩とチューリングラブ歌いたかったのか？
...you wanted to sing "Tuning Love" with Okayu-senpai?
今度歌おう、おかゆ先輩と！お誘いしよう！
I'll sing it with her next time! I'll invite her!
あー、ちょっと、イライラ...
Ah, I'm getting annoyed...
おかゆ先輩かっこいいんだよなー。
Okayu-senpai is so cool.
どうしたの？
What's wrong?
イライライラして...
I'm getting really annoyed...
うわあ！
Whoa!
るしあ！
Rushia!
お前、お仕置きが必要なようだな！おい、生意気にしてんじゃねーよ、コラ！うらー！
It seems you need a punishment! Hey, don't get cocky with me! Take this!
痛いー！
It hurts!
fancy baby doll
Lyric : 三井 ゆきこ / Music : 太田 雅友
Lyric: Yukiko Mitsui / Music: Masatomo Ota
ピンクのキャミソールを着て 今夜ねえ 遊びに行くわ
Wearing a pink camisole, hey, I'm going out tonight.
スイートな服は宝物
Sweet clothes are my treasures.
君は 少し 恥ずかしそうね
You look a little bit shy.
ハートのネイルのピンクは 本当はちょっと大胆だよ
The pink on my heart-shaped nails is actually quite bold.
12時過ぎのシンデレラ もっと 夢見せて
Cinderella after midnight, show me more dreams.
もっと そばに来て Tonight
Come closer to me tonight.
2人きり Let's party
Just the two of us, let's party.
Happy fancy baby doll
Love me fancy baby doll
世界一 可愛い子に 生まれたかった
I wanted to be born the cutest girl in the world.
Happy fancy baby doll
Love me fancy baby doll
何万回 言われても まだ 不安だわ
No matter how many times you say it, I'm still anxious.
愛してる
I love you.
カートに 溢れてしまうほど
So much it overflows from the cart.
今日は ねえ お買い物の日
Hey, today is shopping day.
スイートな 帽子と手袋
Sweet hat and gloves.
おしゃれ すると キラキラするの
Dressing up makes me sparkle.
大きなハートが欲しい 本当はちょっと弱虫だよ
I want a big heart, I'm actually a bit of a coward.
ジープのブーツに履き替えて もっと 追いかける
Changing into Jeep boots, I'll chase you more.
スイートな女の子 ねえ
A sweet girl, hey...
目指したい Love my heart
...is what I want to aim for. Love my heart.
Happy fancy baby doll
Love me fancy baby doll
世界一 可愛いて 今日も 言ってね
Tell me I'm the cutest in the world again today.
Happy fancy baby doll
Love me fancy baby doll
何万回 生まれても 君に 会いたい
No matter how many times I'm reborn, I want to see you.
本当よ
I mean it.
ハートのネイルのピンクは 本当はもっと大胆だよ
The pink on my heart-shaped nails is actually more bold.
12時過ぎのシンデレラ もっと 夢見せて
Cinderella after midnight, show me more dreams.
もっと そばに来て Tonight
Come closer to me tonight.
2人きり Let's party
Just the two of us, let's party.
Happy fancy baby doll
Love me fancy baby doll
世界一 可愛いて 今日も 言ってね
Tell me I'm the cutest in the world again today.
Happy fancy baby doll
Love me fancy baby doll
何万回 生まれても 君に 会いたい
No matter how many times I'm reborn, I want to see you.
約束よ
It's a promise.
イェーイ！！
Yeah!!
ぺこちゃん！
Peko-chan!
ぺこちゃん！ありがとう！ありがとう！嬉しい！
Peko-chan! Thank you! Thank you! I'm so happy!
こちらこそぺこ！ありがとうぺこ！
Likewise-peko! Thank you-peko!
ありがとう！ありがとう、嬉しい！
Thank you! Thank you, I'm so happy!
誕生日なんだよね。
It's my birthday, right?
一緒に歌えて嬉しかったぺこだよ、Fancy Baby Doll。
I was happy we could sing "Fancy Baby Doll" together-peko.
可愛かったね、私たち、Fancy Baby Doll。
We were cute, weren't we? Singing "Fancy Baby Doll".
やっぱりアイドルぺこなのかな？
I guess we really are idols-peko?
当たり前じゃん、私たちアイドルなんだよ。
Of course! We're idols, after all.
なんかさ、たまごっち全員集合って言われてることあるけどさ...
You know, some people say it's like a Tamagotchi reunion, but...
ほんぺこ、アイドルぺこなんだけど、ぺこらも！
Truly-peko, we're idols-peko! Right, Pekora?
マジで！
Seriously!
してらんないよね！
We can't just accept that!
ほんとぺこー！
Exactly-peko!
頑張りすぎなんだよ、お前。
You're trying too hard.
このさ、ツーショット見たら、もう、一生ヤバくない？
Looking at this two-shot, isn't it amazing?
いや、もうこの、阪神みどりども、
Yeah, this Hanshin-Midoridomo duo,
あー、まさにアイドル、ぺこだったよね、やっぱりね。
ah, it was definitely idol-like, right, Pekora?
でしょ、ターンとか可愛かったし。
Right? The spin and everything was cute.
るしあたちの、パーッて回るやつ。
That part where we went 'pa!' and spun around.
これ、これ、ね！
That one, right!
そうなんだよね。でね、ぺこら...
Exactly. And you know, Pekora...
うん、何ぺこ？
Yeah, what is it?
るしあたちさ、芸人とか言われるじゃん。
We're often called comedians, aren't we?
まあね、言われることが多いぺこですが。
Well, we do get called that a lot, but...
でも、アイドルじゃん。
But we're idols, right?
そうぺこね。
That's right.
だからこそさ、ちょっと今からさ...
That's exactly why, right now...
可愛いポーズ対決しない？
Why don't we have a cute pose battle?
突然ぺこ！？
All of a sudden?!
突然可愛いポーズ対決！？
A sudden cute pose battle?!
そう、アイドルらしい...
Yeah, like an idol...
どっちがアイドルとしての力が強いかっていうのを今決めるぺこ？
So we're deciding which of us has more idol power right now?
今対決するとかどう？
How about we battle right now?
いいよ、かかってきなさいぺこですよ！
Fine, bring it on!
アイドルですから任せなさい、
I'm an idol, so leave it to me,
どんなポーズでもできますぺこですから。
I can do any kind of pose.
一緒にやるの？それとも片方ずつ見せていく感じ？
Are we doing it together? Or showing them one by one?
一緒に、やっぱりみんなにも写真とか撮ってほしいから、
Together, because I want everyone to take pictures,
一緒にパッてやっていこうか。
so let's go 'pa!' together.
オッケーぺこ、うん、よし。
Okay, yeah, alright.
どうしよう、何にしようかな...
What should I do... Let's see...
可愛い、アイドルらしいポーズ...
A cute, idol-like pose...
あれにしよう、ぺこら決めました！
I'll go with that one, I've decided!
早！るしあも決まった。オッケー。
So fast! I've decided too. Okay.
オッケー。
Okay.
じゃ、るしあ、掛け声よろしく。
Alright Rushia, you give the signal.
いくよ、せーの！
Here we go, ready, set...
はい！
Go!
あれ！
Wait!
一緒ぺこ！？
It's the same?!
待って、打ち合わせしてない！
Wait, we didn't even talk about this!
凄くない、これ？打ち合わせしてないからね！
Isn't this amazing? We didn't plan it at all!
凄すぎるぺこ、びっくりしたぺこよ。
That's incredible, I'm really surprised.
もう一個、もう一個決まってる、るしあ決まったんだけど。
One more, I've decided on another one.
もう一個ね、えーっと、待て、えー、あれにしよう。
Another one, huh... let's see, wait, um, let's go with that.
よし、決めた。
Alright, decided.
これで似てたら怖いぺこね。
It would be scary if we match again.
いくよ、せーの！
Here we go, ready, set...
はい！
Go!
おー！
Oh!
違うぺこ、お互い違う！
It's different! We're doing different ones!
これ、体幹が... キツい！体幹がキツいぺこだから！
This is... my core! It's tough on the core!
るしあもキツい、ちょっと...
It's tough for me too, just a bit...
アイドルたるもの、
As an idol,
片足立ちずっとしなきゃいけないぺこなのに。
you're supposed to be able to stand on one leg forever.
ぺこらたちキツかったよ、これちょっと。ラストいこう、ラストで。
This was tough for us. Let's go for the last one.
ラストも最大級の可愛いやつ、
The last one should be the cutest ever,
あれにしようかな。
let's go with that.
やるわよ。早！決まってんのか、どうしようかな、あれにしようかな。
I'll do it. So fast! You decided already? Let's see, maybe that one...
うん、あれにしようかな、うん。
Yeah, let's go with that, yeah.
よし、よし、勝ったな、これ。
Alright, alright, I've won this for sure.
勝ったな、ね！
I've won, for sure!
おい、そんな自信があるぺこなのかよ、わかったよ。
Hey, you're that confident? Alright then.
おい、じゃ勝負ぺこでいくよ、いくよ！
Alright, let's go for the final battle!
せーの、はい！
Ready, set, go!
あれ！
Wait!
るしあ、ライブで見せてんじゃねえぺこだよ！売ってんなよ、色を！
Rushia, don't just show off at the live! Don't flirt like that!
こっち見なよ、ちょっと！
Look over here for a second!
これ、二人とも優勝ぺこじゃない、これお互いに可愛いもんね。
Aren't we both winners? We're both cute, after all.
これはちょっともう、どっちかとかなく両方アイドル可愛いということで、
Let's not pick one, we're both just cute idols,
この辺にしとく？今日は。
should we leave it at that for today?
そうぺこね、うん、ぺこぺこ。
That's right, yeah.
じゃあ、じゃあ、ぺこら、ぺこら、次の曲行きたいからさ、一緒にジャンプしない？
Now, Pekora, I want to go to the next song, so why don't we jump together?
よくある、ジャンプしたら
Like how you're
次のところにいるみたいな感じぺこ？
in the next place after jumping?
そう、やろう、やろう！
Exactly, let's do it!
行くよ、ぺこら、今日ほんとにありがとう。
Here we go, Pekora, thank you so much for today.
こっちこそありがとうぺこ、オッケー！
The pleasure is mine, okay!
次のところまで、せーの！えい！
To the next place, ready, set, go!
よいしょー！
Yoisho!
え、待って、どこから来たの？
Wait, where did you guys come from?
ぺこらと飛んできたんだよ。
I flew here with Pekora.
そうなんだ。
I see.
ファンタジーだから、こういうこともできちゃう。
Since it's fantasy, anything can happen.
今日は、この後ね、
Today, after this,
五人である曲を歌いたくてやって参りました。
we've come here to sing a certain song together.
ある曲？なんだろう？
A certain song? I wonder what it is?
集まってもらいました。わかった、あれでしょ？
We've all gathered here. I know, it's that one, right?
「キラメキライダー☆」とかかな？ちょっと待って、違うよ！
Is it 'Kirameki Rider☆' or something? Wait, no!
五人の曲... わかる人？
Our song... who knows it?
るしあ、忘れないで、絆を。
Rushia, don't forget our bond.
そうじゃないの！
That's not it!
さぁさぁさぁ！
Come on, come on!
おとぶんとか...
Like 'Otobun'...
ねえ！
Hey!
５人だからね、イッツ・ア・ミュージックもね、歌いたかったね！
Since there are five of us, we wanted to sing 'It's a Music' too!
いんたらくとふぁんたじあもね、歌いたいぺこだね！
We want to sing 'Interact Fantasia' too, peko!
歌いたい！歌いたい！
I want to sing it! I want to sing it!
ほら、ほら、ほら！
Look, look, look!
い...
I...
あ、焼肉！
Ah, Yakiniku!
うわあああああ！
Whoaaa!
歌ったね、焼肉。
We did sing 'Yakiniku'.
ほらもう！ぺこらいっちゃって！
Come on! Pekora, go ahead and say it!
いっちゃっていいぺこですか？しかも正解いっちゃうよ？いい？
Can I say it, peko? And I'll give the right answer, okay? Ready?
うん！
Yeah!
いくよ！
Here I go!
ぺこらガチでいっちゃうよ？いいの？本当に？
Pekora's really gonna say it? Is it okay? Truly?
分かるかなぁ？
I wonder if they'll know?
え、待って、他に５人で歌った曲ってなんかあったっけ？
Wait, were there any other songs we sang as five?
もうー！！
Jeez!!
ななびょうし！
Seven beats!
ななびょ... せーの！
Seven bea... one, two!
なびょ！
Nabyo!
うん！
Yeah!
並んでからぺこ、並んでからな！うん、よっ！
Line up first, peko! Line up! Yeah, alright!
いきます！
Here we go!
いんたらくとふぁんたじあ！
Interact Fantasia!
いんたらくとふぁんたじあ
Interact Fantasia
いんたらくとふぁんたじあ / Lyric / Music: 渡辺翔
Interact Fantasia / Lyric / Music: Sho Watanabe
いんたらくと
Interact...
ふぁんたじあ
Fantasia...
いんたらくと、ふぁんたじあ、いんたらくと、ふぁんたじあ！
Interact, Fantasia, Interact, Fantasia!
そうワクワク止まらないね、いんたらくとふぁんたじあ
That excitement just won't stop, Interact Fantasia
Wake up fantasia、きっとここが消えないフェアリーテイル
Wake up fantasia, this will surely be an everlasting fairy tale
Wake up fantasia、レッツ・ゴー、イェイ！
Wake up fantasia, let's go, yay!
ぺこら！
Pekora!
だんだん目指すは頂点だ、ほらついてくるぺこ
Aiming higher step by step to the peak, hey, follow me, peko
るしあ！
Rushia!
ちょっと待ってみんなで一緒に、ねぇなんか頼りなくない？
Wait a minute, all of us together, hey, isn't something missing?
ふれあ！
Flare!
怖いものなし進めいざ舞え
Nothing to fear, advance and dance now
のえる！
Noel!
たまには泣いちゃっても前向いていく
It's okay to cry sometimes, just keep looking forward
まりん！
Marine!
あはーい、さて手を取り合ったら冒険の幕が開ける
Ahoy! Now, once we take each other's hands, the curtain rises on adventure
たちまち過ぎてゆく昨日、その目に焼き付け
Yesterday's fading away in an instant, burn it into your eyes
広がる空も海も大地も、重ねあった思い出を溢れさせ
The vast sky, the sea, and the land, let the shared memories overflow
明日へと走り続けよう
And keep running towards tomorrow
果てしない夢を追う真っ直ぐに
Chasing an endless dream, straight ahead
君となら怖くはないから
Because I'm not afraid if I'm with you
戸惑いも全部その背中に預けあい
Entrusting even all our hesitation to each other's backs
未知の道も楽しみながら走れる
Even unknown paths, we can run while enjoying them
心が今を告げる、さあ行くよ
My heart announces the present, let's go
進むべき未来が待っている
The future we should head towards is waiting
他でもない君がいるから
Because you are here, and no one else
繋げよう君と僕の世界、ここから旅は始まってる
Let's connect your world and mine, the journey starts right here
いんたらくとふぁんたじあ、きっとここが消えないフェアリーテイル
Interact Fantasia, this will surely be an everlasting fairy tale
Wake up fantasia、レッツ・ゴー、イェイ！
Wake up fantasia, let's go, yay!
目触れ、ハローエバー、して日常を照らし出すトゥインクル・ウェザー
Gazing, hello ever, twinkle weather that lights up everyday life
退屈にバイバイ、声上げ明日へ付いて来れるよね？トゥワイス・ア・デイ！
Bye-bye to boredom, raise your voice to tomorrow, you can follow me, right? Twice a day!
今駆け出す時が来た、心の準備はオッケー？
The time to dash out has come, is your heart ready?
鐘を鳴らせば伝説が一歩開く
If we ring the bell, a legend will open up step by step
僅かに踏み出した勇気が魔法に変わるから
Because the little courage we took will turn into magic
世界の果ても次元の壁も、吹き飛ばして今君に会いにいこう
Whether the ends of the world or dimensional walls, let's blow them away and go see you now
一緒に飛び出してみない？
Won't you try jumping out together with us?
届かない夢はないどこへでも
There's no dream that can't be reached, to anywhere
君となら辿り着けるから
Because I can reach it if I'm with you
褪せないエールをその両手に握りしめ
Gripping an unfading cheer in both of those hands
白紙の地図を描きまわして駆け出そう
Let's draw on a blank map and dash out
願いとともに歌う聞こえるよ
Singing along with our wishes, I can hear it
まやかしのファンタジーであっても
Even if it's a deceptive fantasy
出会いは幻じゃないから
Because our meeting is not an illusion
繋げよう君と僕の声、奇跡を奏で合うシンフォニー、いつまでも
Let's connect your voice and mine, a symphony playing miracles together, forever
ちょっと強くなりたくて
Wanting to become a little stronger
ずっと笑い合いたくて
Wanting to always laugh together
色づく気持ち今結ぶ、君と出会えたよ
Binding these budding feelings now, I was able to meet you
失敗も後悔もさせるわけないよ
I won't let there be failures or regrets
だって毎日楽しすぎでしょ？
Because every day is just too fun, isn't it?
ときめきの先の先へ
Towards what lies beyond the excitement
裸足で駆け抜けろ
Run through it barefoot
いんたらくと、ふぁんたじあ、いんたらくと、ふぁんたじあ！行こう！
Interact, Fantasia, Interact, Fantasia! Let's go!
果てしない夢を追う真っ直ぐに
Chasing an endless dream, straight ahead
君となら怖くはないから
Because I'm not afraid if I'm with you
...忘れないから
...because I won't forget.
戸惑いも全部　その背中に
I'll leave all my hesitation on your back,
預け合い　未知なき道も
entrusting each other, even on pathless roads,
楽しみながら走れる
we can run while enjoying ourselves.
心がいまを告げる
My heart tells me about the present.
さあ行こう　進むべき未来が待ってる
Let's go! The future we should head for is waiting.
ほかでもない君がいるから
Because you, and no one else, are here.
繋げよう　君と僕の世界
Let's connect your world and mine.
いつまでも　旅は終わらない
Forever, the journey will never end.
いんたらくとふぁんたじあ
Inter-act Fantasy.
みんな見て
Everyone, look!
ウェルカムファンタジア
Welcome Fantasy.
イェーイ！
Yay!
いんたらくとふぁんたじあでしたー！
That was 'Inter-act Fantasy'!
みんなわかってたねー、さすが！
Everyone knew the dance! As expected!
当たり前ぺこだよ！
Of course, peko!
あたぼうよ、あたぼうよ！
Exactly, exactly!
ライブ以来ぺこだねー。
It's been since the live, peko.
ねー、楽しかった。また歌える時が来るとは思わなんだ。
Yeah, it was fun. I didn't think the time to sing it again would come.
確かにね。
True.
ところでね、みんな、今年も入ったけど。
By the way, everyone, the new year has started.
だね、2022年。
Right, 2022.
みんなのさ、目標聞いてもいいかな？
Can I ask for everyone's goals?
目標？
Goals?
うん、抱負でもいいよ。
Yeah, or resolutions.
これは何？みんなの？自分たちの？
Is this for the group? Or personal?
みんなの。先にるしあから言おうかな。
Group goals. Shall I, Rushia, go first?
いい？
Is that okay?
はい！潤羽るしあ、3期生のみんなと...
Yes! I, Uruha Rushia, want to...
地上波に出たいです！
appear on terrestrial TV with everyone!
せっかく出ましたからね。
Since we've finally made it out here.
まだ5人で出てないぺこだしね、テレビ。
We haven't been on TV together as five yet, peko.
そう、確かにな。
Yeah, true.
じゃ、次はね、ノエル！
Then next is Noel!
はい！団長はね、えー、どうしようかな...
Yes! For me, hmm, let's see...
3期生のみんなでお揃いのものとかをちょっと付けたりとか。
I want us to wear matching things together.
あー、いいなー！やりたい！
Ah, that's nice! I want to do that!
女の子だね、可愛い。
So girly, how cute.
お揃いしたいね。
I want to match.
好きだよねノエルね、お揃いとか。くれるもんね、お土産とか。
You like matching things, don't you, Noel? You give us souvenirs.
なんか見ると探しちゃう。あ,これ水色だからぺこらだ、とか。
I end up looking for them. Like, 'this is light blue so it's Pekora's'.
あー、可愛い。いつもありがとねー。
Ah, how cute. Thanks as always.
まだぬいぐるみ大事にしてんぜ。
I'm still taking good care of the plushie.
ありがとう！じゃ、次、ぺこちゃん！
Thank you! Next, Peko-chan!
はい！ぺこらはねー。
Yes! For Pekora...
これは多分大人の方たちの協力がないとできないぺこですけど...
This probably won't be possible without management's help, but...
ホロライブファンタジー3期生のギャルゲーを誰か作ってください！
Please, someone make a gal game for the 3rd gen!
ギャルゲー！？ぺこらが言うと意外。
A gal game!? Coming from Pekora, that's unexpected.
めっちゃいいじゃん！
That would be so good!
ギャルゲーじゃなくてもいいぺこなんだけど、3期生でのゲームとか欲しいな。
It doesn't have to be a gal game, but I'd like a game featuring us.
今年はそう思ったぺこかな。
That's what I thought for this year, peko.
サバゲーのほうが合ってそうだけどね。
A survival game seems more fitting though.
攻略したい！
I want to clear it!
攻略してほしいなー。いいな、めっちゃいいじゃん。
I want people to clear it. That's so great.
じゃ、ちょっとゲームもお願いします。
So, please make a game too.
お願いします！
Please!
次、マリン！
Next, Marine!
えー、そうだね、じゃあ地上波っていうのが出たから、アニメにしましょう！
Right, since terrestrial TV was mentioned, let's go with an anime!
アニメ！いいなー。
Anime! That's nice.
地上波のテレビに出たらどうせ滑り散らかすんで。
If we go on terrestrial TV, we'll just end up bombing anyway.
やめてやめて！安全安全！
Stop that! Safety first!
アニメ化でいきましょう。
Let's go with an anime adaptation.
アニメしたいな、キャラクターに。声当てたいね。
I want an anime. I want to voice the characters.
演技練習しなきゃ。頑張んないとね。
We'll have to practice acting. We've got to work hard.
次、フレア！
Next, Flare!
そうだね。やっぱり地上波は出たいなと思うんだけど。
Right. I think I also want to be on terrestrial TV.
私たちが一番合ってるやつ、そうだな。
The one that fits us best... let's see.
M-1とか？
Maybe M-1?
お前一人で出ろよ！
You go out there alone!
なんでだよ！みんなで一緒に出ようよ！
Why!? Let's all go together!
芸人と化した3期生。M-1に出るとは。
The 3rd gen has turned into comedians. To think we'd enter M-1.
誰がネタ披露するんだよ。
Who's going to perform the routine?
まあ、みんなでいろんなジャンル出たいねってことで。
Well, the point is we want to appear in various genres together.
みんなで一致してるのはやっぱりテレビとかゲームだったね。
What we all agreed on was TV and games after all.
やりたいね。絶対叶えようね、今年。
I want to do it. Let's definitely make it happen this year.
やんぞー！みんなこっちもよろしくね！
Let's do this! Everyone, please support us here too!
じゃあさ、みんなでスクショ...
Well then, let's take a group screenshot...
あ！
Oh!
いいね！
Nice!
５人でね！
With the five of us!
そろか、そろか！記念写真だ！
Let's line up! It's a commemorative photo!
どんなにする？ちょっとみんなでこう...
What pose should we do? Let's all get close...
るしちゃん真ん中にしなよ！
Put Rushia in the center!
ありがと、ありがとー！
Thank you, thank you!
これさ、お誕生日おめでとうの...
This is for the birthday celebration...
ちょっとー！邪魔なんだけど！被ってる！
Hey! You're in the way! You're covering me!
マリンが隠れちゃってる！
Marine is hidden!
イエーイ！いっぱい撮ってね！
Yay! Take lots of photos!
これさ、お客さんの方の反対側向いても撮りたくない？
Don't you want to take one facing the audience too?
あ、いいね！回ろ回ろ！
Oh, nice! Let's turn around!
よくライブであるやつ！
This is like what you see in lives!
エモい！すごい！
So emotional! Amazing!
しゃがんで撮ろっか。
Let's take one crouching down.
るしあ、ブリっ子するわ！
Rushia is going to do a cute pose!
ちょっと、マリンはどうしたらいいの？
Wait, what should Marine do for a cute pose?
もうちょっとしゃがんだ方がいいかな？
Maybe crouching more is better?
ちょっと、お前のスカート...こうか！
Wait, your skirt... like this!
いいね、いいね！撮って！
Nice, nice! Take the photo!
いっぱい撮ってね！
Take lots of photos!
カメラもっと上、上から！
Camera more from above, from above!
ここにみんなのサインを入れたいね。
I want to put everyone's signature here.
いいんじゃない？いいね！
Wouldn't that be nice? It's good!
撮れた？可愛い！
Did you get it? So cute!
時間も迫ってきたんで、みんな。
Time is running out, everyone.
今日は本当にありがとう！
Thank you so much for today!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
今年もどうかみんなで仲良く過ごしましょう！
Let's all spend this year getting along well too!
じゃあみんな、また遊ぼう！
Well then everyone, let's play again!
あそぼー！バイバイー！
Let's play! Bye-bye!
思ひ恋ふ
Omoi-Koi-Fu
Lyric / Music: すこっぷ
Lyric / Music: Sukoppu
私はいつも意気地なしで
I've always been a coward,
何をするにも怖くて
afraid of everything I do.
すぐ諦めちゃうんだ
I end up giving up right away.
自信だって全然なくて
I have no confidence at all.
人の背中ばかり見ていた
I only looked at people's backs.
それでいいと思ってた
I thought that was fine.
だけど振り返った
But when I looked back,
あなたが笑ってくれたこと
you were there, smiling at me.
何を話したのかも覚えていないけれど
I don't remember what we talked about,
散らばる言葉は春の匂いがした
but the scattered words smelled of spring.
これが恋なんだって
I realized for the first time,
初めて気付いたんだよ
“This is what love is.”
出会えたことが　話せたことが
Meeting you, talking with you,
こんなに嬉しくて
made me so happy.
確かめたいんだ
I want to make sure
溢れ出すこの想いを
of these overflowing feelings.
もっと近くで伝えられたらいいのに
If only I could convey them from closer by,
だけど
but...
今の私では
as I am now,
だめなんだ
I’m not good enough.
私はいつでも不器用で
I've always been clumsy,
うまく言葉が出なくて
and couldn't find the right words.
思っていることが
If only my thoughts
きれいに伝わればいいのに
could be conveyed beautifully.
あなたのことばかり見ていた
I was only looking at you,
偶然を期待しては
hoping for a coincidence,
もしかしてなんて
thinking “maybe...” and
思い描いたりして
imagining things.
だけどふとした時に
But at a sudden moment,
思いがけず気づいたんだ
I realized unexpectedly,
あなたの視線の先にいる人のこと
the person at the end of your gaze.
こんなに痛いんだって
“It hurts this much.”
初めて思い知るんだ
I realized for the first time.
今のままでも幸せだって
“I’m happy as I am,”
思ってたはずなのに
I should have thought that, but...
止まることのない
These unending
思いは涙に変わり
feelings turn into tears,
心配なんてしてほしいわけじゃないのに
even though I don't want you to worry about me.
でもね
But you know...
やっぱり少しだけ
after all, just a little bit,
されたいな
I want you to worry about me.
夜明けになると
When dawn comes...
...遠く...
...Far away...
痛くても　辛くても
Even if it hurts, even if it's painful,
私が見つけた　私だけのこの気持ちは
these feelings I've found that are mine alone,
離したくないよ
I don't want to let them go.
これが恋なんだって　初めて気づいたんだよ
I've finally realized that this is love.
風に揺られてどこを向いても　あなたへ導くんだ
Swayed by the wind, no matter where I look,
it leads me to you.
誰よりもきっと　あなたのことが好きだよ
I'm sure I love you more than anyone else.
もっと近くで　この気持ち伝えたいの
I want to convey these feelings from even closer.
だから　こんな私では...
So, for someone like me...
だめですか？
Am I not enough?
みんな、お誕生日配信見てくれて本当にありがとう！
Everyone, thank you so much for watching my
birthday stream!
どうだったかな？
How was it?
るしあは今日本当に素敵な一日になれたよ。
Rushia had a truly wonderful day today.
お誕生日配信、見に来てくれて本当に本当にありがとう。
Thank you so, so much for coming to see my
birthday stream.
そして、お誕生日記念として販売するグッズの案内をするね。
And now, I'll give you some information about
the birthday goods we're selling.
それではまず、1点目はこちら。
First of all, here's the first item.
やすゆき先生描き下ろしの、花嫁るしあアクリルスタンド！
The 'Bride Rushia' Acrylic Stand, illustrated by
Yasuyuki-sensei!
見て見て！
Look, look!
すっごく可愛くない？
Isn't it super cute?
めちゃくちゃ綺麗じゃない？
Isn't it incredibly beautiful?
もうこれはね、るしあみんなのお嫁さんになります！
With this, Rushia will become everyone's bride!
可愛いでしょ？
Cute, right?
もうお部屋とかね、パソコンデスクの周りとか、君の近くに、すぐ傍に置いといてください。
Please put it in your room or on your PC desk...
Keep me close by your side.
るしあがずっと見てるからね。
Because Rushia will be watching you forever.
そして2点目は、るしあと一生一緒エンゲージリングです！
And the second item is the 'Together with Rushia
Forever' Engagement Ring!
うわあー！
Whoa!
これはこれは、結婚指輪というやつではないですか？
Isn't this... a wedding ring?
どうですか？これは、君たちと一緒に付ける指輪です。
What do you think? This is a ring to wear
together with you all.
いや、ちょっとドキドキしちゃうね。
Man, my heart is racing a bit.
とっても綺麗で可愛くない？
Isn't it very beautiful and cute?
もう生涯に一度の代物ですよ。
It's a once-in-a-lifetime item.
素敵でしょ？
Lovely, isn't it?
いやこれはみんなと一緒にぜひぜひぜひ付けたい。
Man, I really, really, really want to wear this
with everyone.
るしあ毎日これを付けて配信します。
Rushia will wear this during my streams
every day.
そして、最後の3点目はこちら。
And finally, the third item is this.
さかあな先生描き下ろしの、ペアマグカップセットになります！
A pair mug set, illustrated by Sakaana-sensei!
いや、ペアだらけだね。
Man, it's full of 'pairs'.
見て、このマグカップも。
Look at these mugs too.
朝起きた時とか、寝る前とか休憩とか、もうずっと一緒なんだよ。
When you wake up, before you sleep, during breaks...
We'll be together all the time.
可愛いでしょ？
Cute, right?
これはね、るしあバージョンとふぁんでっどちゃんバージョンのコップになります。
These are mugs in a Rushia version and a
Fandead-chan version.
いや、みんなと使いたいな。
Man, I want to use them with everyone.
君とお揃いいっぱいになったね。
Now we have so many matching items.
これもね、配信しながらるしあ使って飲んでるから。
I'll be using mine to drink from during my
streams too.
君たちもるしあの配信見ながらこれを使って飲めば、もうるしあたち結婚生活だね。
If you all use yours while watching my streams,
it'll be like we're living a married life.
はい、こんなにね、素敵なグッズたくさん盛りだくさん、どうですか？
So, what do you think of all these wonderful goods?
そしてなんと、なんと、なんと！誕生日記念フルセットは、今紹介したグッズに...
And! And! And! The Birthday Commemorative Full Set
comes with the goods I just introduced, plus...
るしあの複製サイン入りポストカードが付いてきます！
a postcard with Rushia's duplicated signature!
でっ、でっ、でっ、数量限定バージョンのものには...
And, and, and, for the limited-quantity version...
るしあの直筆サインメッセージ入りポストカードが付いてきます！
it comes with a postcard featuring a handwritten
signature and message from Rushia!
直筆ですよ、直筆。どぉどぉどぉどぉ。
It's handwritten! Handwritten! Whoa, whoa.
要チェックですよ、要チェック。
Be sure to check it out, okay?
周年記念のサインも書き終わってるので、改めてみんなのために...
I've finished signing the anniversary ones,
so once again, for everyone...
愛情、覚、覚、込めたメッセージを書いていきます。
I'll be writing messages filled with love and
care.
よかったらみんな、どんどん感想ツイートなどなどしていってね。
Please feel free to keep tweeting your thoughts
and stuff, okay?
そしてまだ、実はこれで終わりでなくて...
And actually, that's not all yet...
もう少し見てもらいたいものがあります。
There's something else I want you to see.
行きます。デデン！
Here we go. Ta-da!
みんなー！
Everyone-!
今日は本当に、本当に、生誕祭ライブ...
Today was truly, truly, a birthday live...
遊びに来てくれて本当にありがとうね。
Thank you so much for coming to hang out.
何か気づいたことある？
Did you notice anything?
この猫耳とツインテールとチョーカー！じゃじゃーん！
These cat ears, twin tails, and choker! Ta-da!
こちらは実は、るしあの誕生日だからといって、
Actually, since it's Rushia's birthday,
やすゆきお父様が、るしあにプレゼントしてくださいました！
Yasuyuki-otosama gave these to me as a present!
へへへ。可愛いね。似合ってるね。あはは！
Hehe. They're cute, right? They suit me. Ahaha!
ということで、この姿でも配信していくので、
So, I'll be streaming in this form too,
みんなこれからも仲良く、るしあと遊んでいってください。
so everyone, please continue to get along and play with Rushia.
そして、グッズなんですけど、10時から販売されるので、
Also, about the merch, it goes on sale at 10 PM,
概要欄から飛んでいって、どんどんグッズをお手に取ってみてください！
so please follow the link in the description and get your hands on some!
サイン入り、チェキですよ！
There are signed polaroids!
他にもね、素敵な指輪など、マグカップなどたくさんあるので、
There are also many other things like lovely rings and mugs,
みんな良かったら、たくさん、そばに置いてみてください。
so please keep them close to you if you'd like.
本当に、本当に、今日は素敵な一日をありがとうございました！
Really, really, thank you so much for such a wonderful day today!
みんな、大好きだよ！本当にありがとう。
Everyone, I love you! Thank you so much.
みんな、せーの！
Everyone, on three!
おつるしー！
Otsu-Rushi!
ありがとう。
Thank you.